Xiao Ma

721 Broadway, 4th floor New York, NY 10003 Portfolio GitHub +1.929.215.7159 emailme.mx@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

As a Creative Technologist with three years of experience in computer software engineering, I'm seeking an internship in the field of Creative Technologist and User Experience Engineering. My work ranges from creative coding, front end, installation, to engaging interactions and augmented reality.

EDUCATION

New York University, USA	Interactive Telecommunications Program Master's Candidate	2017.09 – Present
Newcastle University, $\cup K$	Creative Arts Practice Master Degree of Arts	2016.09 – 2017.08
South China University of Technology, China	Computer Software Engineering Bachelor Degree of Engineering	2012.09 – 2016.06

WORK EXPERIENCE

Design Technologist Intern Guangzhou Midia Information Technology Ltd, Guangzhou, China 2015.05 - 2015.09

2015.12 - 2016.05

- Developed functional prototypes for both website and mobile platforms
- Designed interaction for both the website and mobile platforms

PROJECTS

Urban Maze Exploration Unity3D, ARKit, MapBox	2018.03 – 2018.03
 An AR project exploring the possibilities of multiple users in urban areas based on geolocation information. Individual project 	
Future Forest Experience JavaScript, Installation	2017.10 – 2017.12
 An immersive future forest experience inspired by the Japanese rock garden Project Leader, in charge of designing the whole project, implementing the tree and the water animations 	
Sundial Arduino, Installation	2017.10 – 2017.10
 A dynamic sculpture simulating the sundial system Individual project 	
Crime Prediction Processing3	2017.05 – 2017.05
 A project based on weather condition to predict crime committed Collecting and visualizing data from the Internet 	

• A system based on Python and OpenCV to simulate the traffic surveillance

Traffic Surveillance System | Python, OpenCV

• In charge of designing and implementing the visual identity part of the system

- A camera installed on the door to count the number of the people passing through the door
- Using C++ and OpenCV with environment light learning to create a counter for counting the number of people passing through the door

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming: C++, OpenCV, JavaScript, Python, C#, Java, ARKit, Tensorflow, Processing, P5.js
- Design: Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator, Framer, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Adobe XD, Sketch, Invision, Principle
- Game Development: Unity 3D, Unreal 4, Cinema 4D
- Other: Photography, Documentary Film

RECOGNITIONS AND AWARDS

- Red Burns Scholarship | NYU ITP 2017-2018
- Best Original Work | Memory of Campus Activity 2014
- Second Prize | "TCL Communication Cup" College Students' Programming Contest 2012.12